#### 753 Linden Ave San Bruno, CA 94066

# **Jake Dudum**

#### Full Stack Web Developer

Performance-driven and motivated Full Stack Web Developer with 1 years of experience participating in both front end and back end development. Possess a strong attention to detail, well-developed time management skills, and ability to work under pressure.

(650)-515-7204 jakedudum@gmail.com

# **Work Experience**

### **Learning Assistant**

## **Trilogy Education**

03/2020-Present

Remote

Assisted student learning through the use of Trilogy Educations Trilobot on Slack which connected the Learning Assistant team with over 10,000 students across the US.

Answered coding questions ranging from front end UI problems to back end database issues and concerns. Facilitated continual learning by responding to questions with appropriate documentation and discussions on question topics.

## **Teaching Assistant**

#### Trilogy Education

02/2020-Present

Remote

Handled management of Gitlab repository for class which included student activities, homeworks, and projects.

Graded homework assignments and group projects. Provided instruction on best coding practices and the art of "Google-Fu" to students.

Consistently received positive evaluations from students.

# **Substitute Teaching Assistant** Trilogy Education

09/2019-02/2020

San Francisco, CA

Subbed for Teaching Assistants at UC Berkeley Extension San Francisco location.

Helped manage the classroom environment. Encouraged student success and helped motivate student driven learning.

## **Education**

## **UC Berkeley Extension**

05/2019-08/2019

A 12-week intensive full-time summer program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, and React.

## **University of San Francisco**

08/2011-11/2016

Studied CS and acquired over 24 credits in the subject. Classes included Data Structures and Algorithms, Intro to Computer Science 1 & 2, as well as Software Development.

## **Technical Skills**

#### **Technologies**

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Node, Express

#### Frameworks/Libraries

jQuery, React, Bootstrap, Materialize

#### **Databases**

MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase

#### Tools

Visual Studio Code, Git Version Control, Heroku

update whenever a user makes changes.

## **Projects**

#### **Jumble**

A project management tool to help users stay on track. Utilized React state components to live update the projects budget, tasks, and problems charts. Charts.js was used to visualize all of the data being stored for each project and through React the charts

#### **Bark**

Developed an app with similar functionality as <u>Yik Yak</u>. Site features user login with posting capabilities that include photos, gifs, titles, times stamps, and a simple like system.

Data is stored using a relational database to associate users to post and posts to locations.

#### Where2P

An app developed to help people find nearby restrooms. Users are able to find bathrooms using geolocation or enter in a street address manually.

Each bathroom features user reviews that are stored with Firebase.

## Soft Skills

Problem Solving Ability To Work Under Decision Making Pressure Time Management Adaptability

Willingness To Learn Communication
Teamwork

## **Volunteer Experience**

#### Comida For Familias, Inc.

Full Stack Web Developer

03/2020-Present

Remote

Maintained and updated main company website. Helped to configure, revamp front-end, and launch TasteMatch app.

Worked alone and as part of a small team of three to complete coding assignments.